<record xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <dc:title>Risk Communication and Climate Justice Planning: A Case of Michigan’s Huron River Watershed</dc:title>
  <dc:description>abstract: Communicating climate risks is crucial when engaging the public to support climate action planning and addressing climate justice. How does evidence-based communication influence local residents’ risk perception and potential behavior change in support of climate planning? Built upon our previous study of Climate Justice maps illustrating high scores of both social and ecological vulnerability in Michigan’s Huron River watershed, USA, a quasi-experiment was conducted to examine the effects of Climate Justice mapping intervention on residents’ perceptions and preparedness for climate change associated hazards in Michigan. Two groups were compared: residents in Climate Justice areas with high social and ecological vulnerability scores in the watershed (n=76) and residents in comparison areas in Michigan (n=69). Measurements for risk perception include perceived exposure, sensitivity, and adaptability to hazards. Results indicate that risk information has a significant effect on perceived sensitivity and level of preparedness for future climate extremes among participants living in Climate Justice areas. Findings highlight the value of integrating scientific risk assessment information in risk communication to align calculated and perceived risks. This study suggests effective risk communication can influence local support of climate action plans and implementation of strategies that address climate justice and achieve social sustainability in local communities.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Cheng, Chingwen (ASU author)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Tsai, Jiun-Yi (Author)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Yang, Y. C. Ethan (Author)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Esselman, Rebecca (Author)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kalcic, Margaret (Author)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Xu, Xin (Author)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Mohai, Paul (Author)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Herberger Institute for Design and the Arts</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>The Design School</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Landscape Architecture</dc:contributor>
  <dc:identifier>DOI: 10.17645/up.v2i4.1045</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>ISSN: 2183-7635</dc:identifier>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:format>17 pages</dc:format>
  <dc:relation>URBAN PLANNING</dc:relation>
  <dc:identifier>Cheng, C., Tsai, J., Yang, Y. C., Esselman, R., Kalcic, M., Xu, X., &amp; Mohai, P. (2017). Risk Communication and Climate Justice Planning: A Case of Michigan’s Huron River Watershed. Urban Planning, 2(4), 34. doi:10.17645/up.v2i4.1045</dc:identifier>
  <dc:type>Article</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/2286/R.I.47684</dc:identifier>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
  <dc:date>2017-10-12</dc:date>
  <dc:identifier xml:lang="eng">item:47684</dc:identifier>
</record>
